WALTER C. ROBLES

wrobles68@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/wcrobles https://www.behance.net/wcrdesign https://github.com/wrobles1968

323-610-1769

Summary of Qualifications

Senior graphic designer and creative director with extensive experience in developing communication materials and strategies using various production techniques related to the development of technical and non-technical material, both written and graphical.

Core Competencies

Project Management

- Resource and project planning experience
- Resolve complex issues and improve processes
- Experience in gathering business requirements

Integrated Media

- Marketing coordinator products and service
- Expert in the design and branding
- Experience in graphic design and web design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BNM PUBLICITY GROUP

Creative Director

September 2010 - Present

Responsible for the management and design of integrated media for various clients.

- Serve as Creative Director responsible for design and layout L.A. Style Mix entertainment magazine this included overseeing the press run and distribution.
- Serve as Web site administrator for Soledad Enrichment Action charter school redesign for better political awareness.
- Researched and develop "Tiki" branding for Trader Vic's at LA Live through design of integrated media.

Southern California Edison, Irwindale, CA

Business Analyst 2

September 2010 – February 2018

Customer service responsible for handling and resolving 200 customer accounts daily.

- Worked with various systems to perform in depth account analysis so customers are billed in a timely manner.
- Served on Customer Service Week committee to promote and set up the customer service week events improving morale to 250 employees in Customer service billing.
- Developed communications plan for Grassroots process improvement team to establish process improvement culture.
- Led a committees that designed and implemented an "End of Year" event, including location logistics, fundraising and project planning. The efforts resulted in raising \$18,000 to put together the event.
- Analyze and create a One on One tool, benefiting the work environment improving communication between supervisors and subordinates.

COUNTY OF LOS ANGELES PUBLIC LIBRARY, DOWNEY, CA Head of Graphics Division

December 2008-September 2010

Supervised the development and design of communication materials and fabrication projects.

- Demonstrated general knowledge of and experience with production art and design, including communication strategies and production techniques related to the development of community outreach materials, both written and graphical.
- Determine and direct all fabrication of signage and structural construction in new areas of library facilities giving me final approval on all design work.

Walter C. Robles Experience/2

Managed a budget reduced by 60% by opting for more inexpensive materials and house stock used in production of promotional material while establishing a trend of more paperless documents leading to limit cost impact.

Designed the official centennial anniversary logo commemorating 100 years County of Los Angeles Public Library.

SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA EDISON, VARIOUS LOCATIONS

Administrative Assistant (Contract Assignment - Volt)

March 2008-December 2008

Analyzed the Direct payment program and presented its positive results to management and laying future groundwork for SCE future Electronic Fund Transfer.

Communication Specialist 3 (Contract Assignment - Volt)

November 2007–March 2008

Collaborate with Subject Matter Experts on design projects including newsletters, large displays, and communication brochures using best practices like determining needs, developing action plans, and identifying deliverables.

PENTEL OF AMERICA, LTD, ONTARIO, CA **Graphics/Web Project Manager**

June 2006 - July 2007

Served as subject matter expert over graphics division during restructuring of marketing and promotion.

- Supervised and was responsible for hiring new staff, SKU reduction, streamlining design processes, product development and department relocation. Improving logistics and saving \$5 million dollars.
- Responsible for production of packaging including blister packs, header cards, master cartons, dozen boxes, and large Duratrans displays that involve preparation for electronic prepress.

TROJAN BATTERY COMPANY, SANTA FE SPRINGS, CA

July 2000 - June 2006

Marketing Specialist

Served as senior graphic designer responsible for all integrated marketing ideas and development.

- Managed multiple task driven design projects like collateral, label design, point of purchase, print ads, promo items, large Duratrans displays, and web site pages.
- Led a project team in marketing to successfully bring graphic design capabilities in-house from an outsource ad agency saving the company \$80,000 annually and giving the marketing department more flexibility and control.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science, Minor in Business and a certificate in Marketing Management CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LOS ANGELES

Web Master Certificate: Web design specialist

CALIFORNIA STATE POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY, POMONA

Associates Degree in Art and Design with honors

CERRITOS COLLEGE

Certificate Project Management & Business Analyst

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE

SPECIAL SKILLS AND TRAINING

Software: Microsoft Office Suite -Word, Excel, Visio, Access, PowerPoint, and SAP

Design Software: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, In-design, Wordpress, Dreamweaver-HTML 5, CSS